# **Jesse Gallagher**

200 South Line Street, Unit 151, Lansdale, PA 19446 • 610-804-8550 • jesse@secondfoundation.org

# **Summary of Qualifications**

I have been doing Lotus Domino development and administration for the past six years, giving me fluency in its data structuring, performance optimization, and replication/clustering setups.

I have worked extensively with XPages for the last several years, using my blog (http://frostillic.us/) to explore the best ways to write XPages applications and to push the platform forward. I have published a project that adds Ruby language support to XPages (http://frostillic.us/rix), a legacy-design-element editor for the web (http://frostillic.us/fnv), several utility classes to expand existing controls (such as my DynamicViewCustomizer and code to use legacy Outline elements in xe:navigator trees), as well as numerous other useful code snippets and discussions.

My work at MedConference has primarily involved creating a database template for clients' registration/ tracking web sites and implementing their design requests. This has involved extensive HTML, CSS, and JavaScript work using Prototype, Ext, and Dojo. Additionally, I built the company's project-tracking database and have been building an all-encompassing client portal in XPages to pull data from that tracking database, the individual project databases, and several SQL stores.

My non-XPages work involved many of the trickier aspects of legacy Notes development, such as run-on-server agents to selectively raise permissions, integrating JavaScript frameworks to clean up the old-style markup and allow for Notes-user-side database behavior customization, and using DXL to create a UI for non-designer users to create and modify forms and reporting views on the fly.

Additionally, I have been working on a Ruby wrapper for Domino's C API (http://frostillic.us/capi), giving me experience with Ruby's FFI library, C data structures, and the low-level mechanisms of Domino.

My system administration duties have involved setting up and administering numerous Domino servers, FreeBSD FTP/SFTP servers, and several Hyper-V servers.

## **Experience**

### **Lotus Domino Programmer, MedConference LLC**

Dec. 2005 - Present

MedConference is a web conferencing company focusing on running and managing online events for the Life Sciences industry. During my time there, my primary responsibility has been creating and maintaining our project registration/site database template, integrating with our online conference platform, implementing client site designs, and numerous other project-specific customizations such as custom reports and data integration. In addition, I created and have maintained our internal project-tracking database and numerous other internal applications.

My day-to-day interactions involve receiving specs from and discussing project needs with the program development team, participating in project initiation meetings and ongoing client support as the technical lead, and streamlining internal processes with our operations department.

## Media Specialist, MedConference LLC

**April 2005 - Dec. 2005** 

My time as a media specialist consisted primarily of recording online conferences and editing the audio for use in our OnDemand platform.

## **Freelance Consulting**

circa 2001 - April 2005

Prior to MedConference, I worked freelance, supporting individual clients, and as a consultant with Redwood Training & Consulting, Inc. providing web-site design and creation, computer repair services, network installation, and upgrade assistance.

#### **Education**

#### **West Chester University of Pennsylvania**

2003-2005

BS in Computer Science Minor in French

## **Arizona State University**

2001-2003

#### **Skills**

Most of my development since 2005, both professionally and in my spare time, has been in Lotus Domino, and so I have developed a proficiency in the technologies related to that, such as Domino itself and its data model, XPages, Java, LotusScript, and Lotus's Formula language.

Additionally, since most of my work is web-based, I am very familiar with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, with some experience in the JavaScript toolkits Prototype, Ext, and, more recently, Dojo.

I regularly create open-source code snippets and projects related to Domino, which are found on my blog (http://frostillic.us) and GitHub profile (https://github.com/jesse-gallagher).

My normal development environment is Mac OS X running Domino Designer in Windows via Parallels. Whenever possible, I program in TextMate instead.

Through casual and business use, I have developed a proficiency with Unix (Mac OS, Linux, and FreeBSD) and Windows, maintaining server and client instances of each at various times.